[{"question": "What is an Escape Sequence in C language.?", "option1": "A) An escape sequence is a combination of two characters starting with Back Slash always.", "option2": "B) An escape sequence is usually part of a string to tell compiler to produce New Lines, New tabs, Single or Double quotes etc", "option3": "C) An escape sequence is used to format the output to look in desired way.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C Escape Sequences.", "option1": "A) \\n produces new line.", "option2": "B) \\t produces one tab space (white spaces)", "option3": "C) \\b produces one Backspace", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C Escape Sequences.", "option1": "A) \\r produces one Carriage Return. \\r does not take you to the next line. It takes cursor to only the beginning of same line.", "option2": "B) \\f produces form feed", "option3": "C) \\a produces Alert Sound or Beep Sound from PC motherboard speaker", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C Escape Sequences.", "option1": "A) \\' outputs one Single Quote. Right Single Quote.", "option2": "B) \\\" outputs one Double Quote.", "option3": "C) \\\\ produces one Visible Back Slash \\.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is a format specifier in C language.?", "option1": "A) A format Specifier tells compiler to treat a variable value is predefined way.", "option2": "B) Different format specifiers are used to print different type of data.", "option3": "C) Format specifiers are used to write data to files in a formatted way.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a valid C format specifier.?", "option1": "A) %d prints integer constants", "option2": "B) %u prints unsigned integer constants", "option3": "C) %ld prints signed long and %lu prints unsigned long constants", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C format Specifiers.", "option1": "A) %c prints unsigned or signed character constants.", "option2": "B) %s prints string constants", "option3": "C) %l or %L prints long constants.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about format specifiers.", "option1": "A) %f prints float constants with 6 digits of precision", "option2": "B) %lf prints double constants", "option3": "C) %Lf prints long double constants", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What does C format specifier %W.D\u00a0represent.?", "option1": "A) W represents total number of columns including precision digits.", "option2": "B) D represents number of precision digits out of W columns.", "option3": "C) Plus(+) before W.D is for Right Alignment. Minus(-) before W.D is for Left Alignment", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a C Formatted Input Output function below.", "option1": "A) printf(), scanf()", "option2": "B) sprintf(), sscanf()", "option3": "C) fprintf(), fscanf()", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a\u00a0C unformatted input output function below.", "option1": "A) gets(), puts()", "option2": "B) getchar(), putchar()", "option3": "C) A & B", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    int a=123;\n    printf(\"*%06d*\",a);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) *123*", "option2": "B) *6123*", "option3": "C) *000123*", "option4": "D) *006123*", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    int a=123456;\n    printf(\"*%03d*\",a);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) *123*", "option2": "B) *6123*", "option3": "C) *123456*", "option4": "D) *012345*", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    int a=6543;\n    printf(\"*%5d,*%-5d*\",a,a);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) *56543,*56543*", "option2": "B) * 6543,*6543 *", "option3": "C) *6543 ,* 6543*", "option4": "D) *6543,*6543*", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    float a=654.123456f;\n    printf(\"%3.3f,%3.2f\",a,a);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) 654,654", "option2": "B) 654.123456,654.123456", "option3": "C) 654.123,654.12", "option4": "D) 654.000,654.00", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]=\"123\";\n    printf(\"*%4s*%-4s*\",str,str);\n    return 0;\n}", "option1": "A) *4123*4123*", "option2": "B) * 123*123 *", "option3": "C) *123 * 123*", "option4": "D) *123*123*", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about sprintf and sscanf functions.?\nchar str[20];", "option1": "A) sprintf(str,\"formatstring\",variables) prints output to console. sscanf(str,\"formatstring\",&variables) scans keyboard input and copies to str.", "option2": "B) sprintf(str,\"formatstring\",variables) prints output to string str. sscanf(str,\"formatstring\",&variables) scans keyboard input and prints to console", "option3": "C) sprintf(str,\"formatstring\",variables) prints output to string str. sscanf(str,\"formatstring\",&variables) scans input from str itself and assigns data to &variables.", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    char ch='A';\n    ch=getchar();\n    putchar(ch);\n    return 0;\n}//input= S", "option1": "A) A", "option2": "B) B", "option3": "C) S", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": " Choose a correct C statement.?", "option1": "A) SCANF can accept all types of data from keyboard including numbers and strings", "option2": "B) GETS can accept only one String of any length and any number of words. GETCHAR can accept only one character constant from keyboard.", "option3": "C) SCANF can accept only single word Strings", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of c program with %* operator.?\nint main()\n{\n    char kh;\n    scanf(\"%*c %c\",&kh);\n    putchar(kh);\n    return 0;\n}//input=G H", "option1": "A) G", "option2": "B) H", "option3": "C) A", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}]
